we have effectively had
general purpose agent development machines for 50 years.
We just called them software engineers.
you never just wrote somebody
a Slack message and expected them to go build an entire system
and just, like, make all the best decisions., right?
Well, nice to meet everybody.
My name is Dru Knox.
I'm the head of product and design here at Tessl.
I'm going to talk today about, using skills as,
like, in a more professional, rigorous, like, software engineering mindset.
Right.
So before I get into this, why should you trust me?
Well, one maybe don't maybe, be sceptical, but,
in my past life before leading product and design here at Tessl,
I was a research scientist leading the language modelling teams
at Grammarly and at a startup
that sadly has not found success yet, called Cantina.
It's a social network, AI first.
And I've done a lot of work on developer tools
and so I do a lot of moonlighting actually writing code,
probably none of it as good as the actual people on Tessl's teams.
So I've thought a lot about this.
I've done a lot of work on this.
I'd like to share some insights.
We'd love questions.
Would love to hear folks like your experience.
What's worked for you.
So I'll try to save lots of time for questions at the end.
But without further ado, you want to work on skills.
Maybe more broadly, you want to work on context for your agents.
So I'm sure folks have heard about context engineering.
It feels like every year we're told that this is the year of something.
I've heard people say that this is the year of context engineering.
Maybe it is, maybe it isn't.
you want to get into context engineering?
Some of you may have already gotten into context engineering.
As you start to work on this, you'll probably go through the same
sort of stages of denial, acceptance, etc.
of this is amazing.
I'm getting good results to suddenly God.
How does any of this work?
Is any of this impactful?
I thought I was an engineer and now I feel like I'm an artist or a librarian.
How do I turn this thing?
Agents context engineering back into the kind of
reliable, predictable engineering that I that I know and love.
So how do we go about doing that?
I think the first thing to realise, just in case anyone has not
sort of conceptualise this, the reason we're all doing context engineering
now is because we've all effectively become tech leads instead of ICs, right?
Like the job in some sense is no longer writing good code.
It's ensuring that good code can be written,
which is things that tech leads know and love or hate already around.
You want to be maintaining good standards, making good decisions,
documenting it, providing the context to the rest of your team,
setting a good quality bar for other engineers to contribute.
We're doing that.
We're just doing that for agents now.
And so what that means is that context is in some sense our new code.
Some people might hate that I say that.
So please take it with a grain of salt. It's a metaphor.
If context is our new code, though, there's things that we expect of our code.
Right? We want a way to know.
Are my programs correct?
Are they performant?
How do I reuse programs?
How do I automate repetitive tasks that are annoying?
And so we've come to expect a lot of answers
here for code like actual code that we write.
I won't belabour the point, but we have all these things, right?
Unit tests, integration tasks, we have analytics and observability.
All these things that give us really good insight into how our programs function.
And the core thing that I want to argue today
is that all of these have an analogue in the world of context engineering.
And if you are sort of diligent about, finding a toolset that does this,
I'm going to show you all Tessl just to illustrate the concepts for you.
Don't have to use Tessl to do any of this.
These are general concepts and patterns.
You can reclaim a lot of that predictability, a lot of that,
sort of rigour that you've come to expect with, with code.
So how can we take all these concepts and apply them to context?
That's the sort of tldr
before we get started,
there's three challenges that make it not a direct comparison, right?
I'm also, as I look at this, just realising the image
that was generated here made a fuzzy correct symbol.
I was looking at it through a fuzzy, display.
So I'm now appreciating my own, my own side of it.
Better. So we have three problems.
The first is that LMS are non-deterministic, right?
You can't just run them once and say, oh, it worked, or oh, it didn't work.
For I now know my context is good, right?
If you tell an agent to do a thing, sometimes it will, sometimes it won't.
I'm sure if I felt this pain many times.
The second is that a lot of times when you create context,
there's not one right or wrong answer, right?
If you write a style guide or if you write a, documentation for a library,
how do you determine that an agent solution did it correctly, right?
You can't just write a unit test and say, we're done. Like it?
You know, it worked. So grading output can be a little challenging.
And finally, there is this new problem
that your programs are now actually things that describe other things.
So you have things in sync.
So you might update your app.
You need to update communication to match it, or you might change a company
flow in one place to make sure that it gets distributed out,
across your organisation.
So sort of a new problem, falls into a lot
of similar automation goals that you might, might have.
So this is like a quick overview slide.
I'm going to dive into each of these.
What is the analogy.
And maybe I'm trying to get a little too cute with this.
But I actually do think there is a direct analogy for all of the,
tools that you've come to expect for development lifecycle.
So I'll quickly run through them.
The first is that, we have things like static analysis and encode land
that is going to look a little bit more like an LM judge, but the same idea of
you want to have a fixed set of best practices, of rules,
of validation, of compiling all those things.
You should be able to run against your context.
To give an example of something we saw recently from a customer using Tessl,
they had added an app sign into one of their files
and didn't realise that that was suddenly triggering the import
mechanisms for most, like agents at MDE.
And it was breaking a whole host of their contexts
without even realising it.
So it seemed silly.
But static validation still important with your context, right?
So you want to have that set up.
You want to have linting, you want to have CI/CD for it.
Unit tests are going to look probably the most different.
Now, instead of defining a unit test that runs, you're going to want to think
through scenarios that sort of stress test the agent.
Does it do what you want
and then run it many times in parallel,
and you're going to take statistical averages.
And so you want to see when I add context, does it actually
improve the sort of average performance of something.
We'll get into that.
That's probably the hardest one.
That's the one where it feels a little different.
It's not going to be quite the same, but you can still get pretty reliable.
Like what I did has improved.
Integration tests, same thing, but testing lots of context at once.
So you're designing scenarios that map to,
using different kinds of context together.
And then we'll get into some of the more esoteric things that Tessl doesn't
even fully support yet,
but we sort of see on our roadmap,
and we think everybody should be thinking about it.
Analytics.
So how can you start actually measuring,
agent sessions in the wild to see what's happening?
Or do we have missing context?
Are things being used correctly, etc..
And then also getting into, automation
like build scripts, how do you make it so that your context is not this static
thing that grows out of date and dies, but as you update
things, you're getting follow up, parse that, auto update your context.
And then package manager reuse
this is actually kind of in the last 2 or 3 weeks, sort of blown up everywhere.
Things like scales say things like Tessl’s context registry.
The idea of like reusable units of context is sort of come onto the scene.
So I'll talk a little bit about unique problems with how you pick
what sort of context manager you're going to use or package manager.
I guess both work.
Okay.
So review formatting and best practices.
Like I said, I'm going to use Tessl as an example here,
but I'll try to explain all of this in a very basic
like you could build all this yourself if you wanted.
There's other tools that do a lot of this.
Not as well as Tessl, though, obviously.
So this is
pretty easy if you look at things like, the skills standard.
So I'm going to use skills as an example here.
If you look at the skills standard there, first of all is a bunch of just static
formatting you can do.
I believe they have a reference CLI implementation that will just
verify your skill compiles.
I, I think everybody who's writing skills should have that in CI/CD
checking that all of your skills are kept up to date.
Like anytime a skill file changes, you should be checking validation.
You would be stunned how many people like
none of their context is loading and they don't even realise that.
So that's a big one.
But also, if you look at anthropic, they have a best practices guide,
and it's basically a list of things like, so here
I have validation tests will tell you if your things compile.
We also will take just anthropic best practices,
and we just run that through LM as judge.
There's a little bit more you can do to tune the prompt to get better results,
but honestly, just put a prompt that has anthropic best practices in it.
It's a great starting point.
And get, information on how specific is your code or your context,
how like, does it have a good concrete case for when it should be used?
I'm sure folks have heard about skills and how they don't activate very often.
There are concrete things you can do without even running the skill to know
how likely is it to trigger?
So these things are cheap.
They're quick. You can put them in CI/CD,
and it's a really
it's a surprisingly large lift to actually making your context useful to you.
Recommend.
Like, this is just kind of like table stakes.
Everybody should have this, just like everybody should have a format or a linter
or things like that.
Bonus points.
You can feed the output of this back into an agent and ask it to fix it.
It's a pretty nice quick loop.
Okay.
Now slightly more complicated, slightly more of like a net new concept.
Right.
So how do you write evals for your context?
So depending on if you're coming from more of a software
background or more of like an ML deep learning background,
this might either be obvious or not so obvious.
But the simple thing that you can do is Or.
Sorry, actually, before I go into this, the thing you're trying to answer is,
is my context actually helping, and how well is the agent
doing at the task that I am trying to achieve?
So if I use this as an example, right.
We have some library that we want the agent to use
and we can see how does it perform without any context.
Right.
We see things like it is not good at using the list function, right.
Maybe it implements it itself, maybe it uses a different,
library or something like that.
It's also bad at async handling, but it's pretty good
at correct stream combination.
It's pretty good at doing zip files.
I'll explain how we measure this in a minute.
You want to understand this so that you can
then understand where do I need to apply context to fix the problem.
So there's a couple things you might get from a view like this.
The first is you might have
written a bunch of context only to realise agent did fine without it.
Like why are you wasting tokens on it?
Or you might actually write something and realise it made performance worse
because something's gone out of date, or it's just added tokens for no reason.
In an ideal world, you see like, it works better with it.
And I've only applied tokens where it matters.
So you want to answer questions like that?
I have here on the right side,
you'll notice that we have like a file viewer here.
All you have to
do to get this set up is write some prompts, right?
Like write some realistic tasks that you want the agent to do that
requires usage of the context that you've created,
and then write a little scoring rubric for what a good solution to that problem
looks like.
The reason I say write a good scoring rubric
and not something like write a bunch of unit tests, is twofold.
The first is that, unit tests are
really obnoxious to write, and they take a long time
and you will quickly find that you just don't do it.
If you have to create example projects and test suites
for every single piece of context that you want to verify.
More importantly, though, I'm sure many of you have seen that agents
do unspeakable things to get unit tests to pass.
And so functional correctness is not the only thing that you're measuring,
especially for context.
A lot of times you want to know, was idiomatic code written or did it use
the library actually wanted it to use instead of implementing its own solution.
And there's really no way to measure this with unit tests.
It's much better to do more energetic review or less judge.
So what you're going to want to do, I see somebody taking photos,
so I'll let them take the photo.
What you want to do is define we put them in markdown file.
So Tessl will generate these and give them to you.
You could write them yourself.
You want to have a prompt that runs through like build this thing.
Here are the requirements.
It should require using the context or at least should require
doing what the context says. Right.
Because you actually want to measure it with them
without context to see if the agent is just smart enough to do it on its own.
And then
importantly, you want to define some kind of grading rubric.
So here this is.
If you were to specify it for Tessl, you'll say
what does a good solution look like.
And you want to be pretty specific here so that you get reliable results
from an LLM.
So you'll say things like the solution should use this exact
API call somewhere in the in the method,
or it should implement or initialise this before it initialises that right.
Like very granular things that can then be checked at the end of the solution
to see what's good code written.
And an important thing to note is that once you have these in place,
like this can take a bit of upfront work.
It's sort of like the new source files that you have to care about
as an agent developer.
But say you get about five of these per piece of context.
That's what we found is like a pretty reliable measure.
Once you have some of these, then you can kind of reap the benefits of it forever,
just like unit tests, right?
You can just every time you make a change, you rerun these.
You see if it helped, if it hurt,
one thing that's different is oftentimes you'll rerun these
without changing the context because there is something else
that's changing, which is the agent in the model.
And so a lot of times you'll rerun what we have found is oftentimes
you can start stripping out your context as agents get better.
Right.
Like we had style guides for Python Calude Opus 4.6 writes pretty damn good Python.
It doesn't need a style guide anymore.
Your evals can tell you that and help you delete context that you don't
no longer need. Save money. Don't pay the tokens.
Every once in a while there will be a regression. There was.
I think it was Gemini.
A recent Gemini was like kind of a smart ass
and thought it didn't need to use tools and read context.
And then we realised, oh, we've had a regression,
we need to go beef up how much we tell the agent to use the context.
Okay,
so repo evals, I talked about integration tests.
I won't go too deep into this because it's basically the same thing.
But you don't want to just test your context in isolation
that can help you like debug.
Are you saying the right things?
Have you has your context grown out of date?
You also want to measure realistic scenarios
in your full coding environment, all your contexts installed.
I was just watching a talk earlier today that described the dumb zone,
which is where you've gotten too much context in your context window.
Because of tools, because of context,
because of all these things where agents just like persistently bad.
So you want to have a few coding scenarios again, like five for
your repo is a fine place to start that just represent an average development
task.
And again, same like, a rubric to grade the output
and just run it every once in a while, see if your tech debt has gotten to a point
where agents
don't understand how to work in your code, have you installed too much context?
Have you installed too many tools? All of that?
This is something that Tessl is building as well.
One thing we found that works pretty well is like scan your previous commits
and turn some of those into tasks, and you can even have
like on a regular cadence, pick like five random commits over the last month.
And this refresh your eval suite.
For folks who are in the ML environment, you have things like input drift
where you want to update your tasks every once in a while.
Don't worry about it.
If that is like seems like too much effort,
just start with something and you can improve it over time.
But yeah, that's a you same idea of task scenarios.
Grading rubrics.
Run them every once in a while.
Make sure you have integrated things.
Okay.
So this one I think is pretty cool but is also kind of scary,
which is you want something like analytics and observability, right.
You've written this context.
You validated the change before you've pushed it out to the repo for everyone.
We do that in software, but then we also still have crash logs.
We have metrics, we have usability funnels, things like that.
This actually does exist for agents.
Just a lot of people aren't paying attention to it.
All of the agents store all of their chat logs in files
in accessible places, and so you can write your own scripts if you'd like.
Tessl has capability to gather these, opt in, of course, because obviously it's
very sensitive information.
You can review those transcripts to see things like were tools called
or how often was this piece of context used?
How often does this pattern get actually meant like actually manifest in the code?
Like how often does it import a library right in the middle of a function
and so there's like
a lot of rich information here that you could just write a quick script,
ask everyone in your team to run it once and just aggregate a bunch of logs
and just review like common problems that you, might want to make new context for.
Great.
One is anytime the agent apologises so you just look for the word sorry,
look for the words. You're absolutely right.
All of these things are good.
Like, oh, maybe we should write something to fix that.
There's a wealth of information, and I guarantee
you've got like 3 or 4 months of cursor logs sitting on all your devs
team, devs machines that you could mine for.
Like, what should we be doing different?
This is my warning.
I've shifted the colour because the next screen is in light mode.
It's a GitHub page, so please prepare your eyes.
How do you keep your context up to date?
Yeah. See, I tried my best.
I really tried to hit the midpoint between black and white.
Sorry.
There is again, you can do something pretty simple here
where you can just set up, there's all kinds of code review tools.
There's cloud code, web.
But I think a general thing to set up in your CI/CD,
if you have created context, is anytime a PR comes up,
have something, scan that PR and then look and say,
is there any markdown file here that should be updated?
Right. So it's not that hard.
Like it really works better than you'd think.
It seems like a really complicated task, but because PR tend to be so focussed,
agents are pretty good at finding out where they should update.
If your powers are too big, maybe it's a good sign to make your PR smaller.
Again, very simple.
So, like, Tessl can automate a lot of this where it says, oh, you added a new case
to your logging levels here, update your documentation as well.
This one is probably the most important
because as your context gets out of date, it just destroys agent performance.
So if you're going
write context, you have to have a solution for keeping it up to date.
Agents are pretty good at doing this, so you don't have to do it by hand.
Don't do it by hand because you won't do it.
Okay.
Last thing, package managers, I mentioned that this one's kind of normal.
You need a package manager if you want to reuse context.
Right?
Like, code review skill, a,
documentation on how to use react, best practices, etc..
So I won't belabour this point.
There's lots of good options out there.
Skills.sh is probably the most popular, though it pains me to say that
Tessl has a package manager as well.
It's not the most popular. I think it's the best.
I won't pitch you on why?
It's the best, but it's the best.
The important thing, though, I'm showing here Tessl's package manager.
Ooh, look, we give you evals, we give you all this useful information.
Two things that are different that you should just think
about when figuring out how to use context.
The first is that, unlike other package managers, a lot of context
you're going to install is going to be describing other package managers.
Right. So I have an example here.
I have documentation on a library that's part of PyPi.
And it describes a particular package at a particular version.
And these are sort of like a net new,
maybe not entirely new, but a it's a weird concept.
And so you just want to think about what is your strategy for matching.
If you have documentation on a library, how do you make sure that as you update
your library, you keep documentation keyed to the same version?
Right? You don't want to say
I'm using context seven on the latest of react,
but actually you're pinned to like react 17 or something for some reason.
So there's lots you can do here.
You can just write again something yourself.
Like a lot of this is not necessarily hard to do, it's
just fiddly to keep updated and keep sort of pace with the
the rate of agent change.
But think about how do you keep your context in sync
with dependencies, in sync with tools or APIs that you're using?
Because it's a new source of drift that you might have to care about?
So that's it.
That's my my walk through.
I'm happy to answer questions now or afterwards.
I think I have a few minutes so I will turn it to questions out.
I should have had a question slide.
But inside you're going to look at this.
That's all right. Thank you very much.
Yeah, we have a few minutes for for questions.
Please wait for the mic if you have a question.
If you do have an excellent question,
then we have some merch that, Sam is modelling over there.
A bag or a fidget spinner or a hat.
Drew takes questions on Tessl but also The Fast
and the Furious and improv comedy.
First.
First, this is true. First question.
Thanks. Hi.
Great presentation.
So what do you see as the in state, like in 12 months or even six months,
if, you know, like Claude 4.6 is just really good and Codex, you know, 5.3
and then when you know, Codex 6 comes out and Claude 5 comes in Gemini.
I mean, do we need a lot of the
scaffolidng or does it go away?
Fantastic question.
I would say
first it's going to split a lot by whether or not you're a greenfield
or brownfield,
like if you've built an app
from the ground up for agents, it's going to be a lot easier
than if you're doing like an enterprise Java app.
So that's one I think the number of things you need context for will go down.
So the example I gave a Python style guide was like all the rage six months ago.
Nobody needs it now.
But describing your custom internal logging solution,
you're always going to have to document
that because like an agent doesn't have access to it, right?
It's not in its training weights.
So there's some amount of knowledge that will always need to be told to the agent.
My expectation is that eventually
you won't be proactively jamming almost any context into an agent's window.
You'll have some kind of signposting like progressive disclosure.
The agent will get to look at it
if it deems it necessary, like a normal developer will,
and then a lot of your usage of context will be applied at review time.
So you will create a review agent that looks for things like did it
break our style guide?
Did it re-implement something?
And it'll just be there for control.
It won't be there to sort of like educate the agent upfront.
I think evals are going to play a big part
in helping you navigate that change, right?
Knowing when it's time to move things out of the context window
into a review or just delete it?
Yes. Thank you.
Next question here.
I wanted to ask about people's depend on us or
so think of like speed and stuff like that.
You know, I would love one pagers.
I think that's right.
I think binary is pretty much the only like we give granularity in Tessl.
If you want to do more.
But if you look agents pretty much always score zero or max score.
So I would say no, you could get away with 0 or 1 and
it would be about the same.
So, I'm an engineer, so
a lot of built solutions really fast.
Would you recommend just using 4.6 to get all the people said very quickly
and then just use that as a baseline, which is not perfect, but just that as
a starting point or would you recommend don't do a full, thorough analysis.
Get a baseline that
so let me make sure I got that right.
But like should you try really hard to optimise what agent you're using and the.
Exactly. Yeah.
Personally I'm busy.
I have a lot to do.
Just start with the best agent.
And then I think what I'd say more is, once you have
some really repetitive tasks, it can be worth it to say, okay,
what is like the best, the cheapest I can get away with.
A lot of times, context will help you use smaller models to do that.
But no, I would say for a day to day like your general driver,
just always crank it to the max unless you have some reason you can't do that.
Things might actually function because you have to talk.
Yeah.
My question is more tools for me.
Like a little technical,
to to,
what would want me to go,
what barrier to if you can use to measure,
point in time.
Well, I will teach you how to input into what the agents do.
You what that is for something like,
that's how it wants to compare.
Desired.
Not too much.
I'm going to throw out maybe spicy take which is that.
Definitely we're not there and I don't think we'll ever be them.
What I mean by that is we have effectively had
general purpose agent development machines for 50 years.
We just called them software engineers.
And in that case, you never just wrote somebody
a Slack message and expected them to go build an entire system
completely unsupervised and just, like, make all the best decisions., right?
Another way of putting this, my wife, who is like a very senior staff engineer
at meta, is like, if you cloned me, I would still code review my code, right?
Like I would never accept anyone to submit things without looking at it.
So personally, I think there will always be a place for a technical
architect, a steward,
somebody who's guiding the sort of quality of the code base.
I think what that role is will change over time.
So right now it's a lot of like in the weeds, very specific decisions.
It's a lot of like reviewing code.
It's mentoring and coaching people up.
And you tend to have like 1 p.m.
to 5 to 10 engineers. Right?
I imagine we'll get to a place where you invert that ratio
and you have one sort of like technical steward whose job is to think
about the overall system design, to be constantly reviewing
agent code, to be reviewing things that people
are building and understanding, like, oh, this is a consistent failure point.
If we abstract this part out, if we build a component that agents can use,
they'll more reliably get better, like one shot success.
And then you have like 5 to 10 more like product design, product
engineering, people who are out sort of exploring the frontier of your
product space and then have this one technical steward
helping them land their code and keep things maintainable and improve,
like improving them over time.
When will we get to that point?
That part I'm less certain of.
Like it could be in two weeks. It could be in two years.
I think it's probably in the order of like single digit years.
Certainly.
I wouldn't be surprised if it was like a completely I native
greenfield project starting within the next year could work in that model.
But certainly for brownfield, I think it'll be harder.
Sweet. Thank you so much. All right.